Finding Aid for Slayton Family Papers, 1849-1955
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Slayton Family papers 1849-1955
Slayton family.
10.5 linear feet (in 11 boxes)
8626 Aa 2
Hillsdale, Michigan family; papers relating to participation of family members in the Civil War, farming in Kent County, Hillsdale College, religion, and daily activities.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Asa Walker Slayton papers were donated by Lewis Reichle (donor no. 1581 ) in 1942 and 1950. The William C. and Julia Slayton papers, and the papers of their children were donated by the Slayton-Dunn estate (donor no. 3361 ) in 1957. Smaller portions came from Hillsdale public librarian Miss Louise Hawkes (donor no. 3754 ) and Jack Northrup (donor no. 3755 ).
The collection is open to research.
The Slayton family were prominent long-time residents of Hillsdale, Michigan, active. Asa Walker Slayton was a farmer and teacher. His brother William C. Slayton was a Kent County farmer. William Slayton's son George A. Slayton taught at Hillsdale College. Other family members were active in Hillsdale County Hillsdale College affairs.
The Slayton Family papers include material relating to participation of family members in the Civil War, farming in Kent County, Hillsdale College, religion, and daily activities. The collection has been arranged by family and family member name. The series in the collection are: Children of Russell and Berthena Slayton, Children of William C. and Sarah M. Slayton, Children of George and Sarah Slayton, and Miscellaneous Papers.
Subjects:
Baptists--Michigan--Hillsdale.; Chautauquas.; Clergy--Michigan.; College Baptist Church (Hillsdale, Mich.); College teachers--Michigan--Hillsdale.; Dunn family.; Education--Michigan--Hillsdale County.; Farmers--Michigan--Hillsdale.; Free Will Baptists (1780?-1911); Grattan (Mich.); Grattan (Mich.: Township); Grant (Mich.); Hillsdale (Mich.); Hillsdale College.; Hillsdale Star Guild (Mich.); Slayton family.; Teachers--Michigan--Hillsdale.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 18th (1862-1865). Company E.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 25th (1862-1865). Company B.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Women--Michigan--Hillsdale.; Women--Michigan--Hillsdale--Societies and clubs.; Women college teachers--Michigan--Hillsdale.; Women in agriculture--Michigan--Hillsdale.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Buildings--Michigan--Lapeer.; Families.; Fort Custer (Mich.); Hillsdale College.; Hillsdale College. Class of 1906.; Hillsdale (Mich.); Lapeer (Mich.)--Buildings.; Michigan. State Home and Training School, Lapeer.; Military camps.; Slayton family.
Contributors:
Dunn, Nettie.; Gates, Helen Dunn, 1857-1910.; Reynolds, Elon G., 1841-; Slayton, Abbie Cyrena, 1884-; Slayton, Asa Walker, 1830-; Slayton, Chester M., b. 1835.; Slayton, George A., b. 1847.; Slayton, George Francis, 1877-1940.; Slayton, Helen Elizabeth.; Slayton, Julia A.; Slayton, Sarah Abby Dunn, 1853-1926.; Slayton, Sarah Augusta, 1886-; Slayton, William C., b. 1823.; Slayton, William Iambert, 1844-1863.; Slayton, Augustus W., 1843-1900.; Sage, James A., b. 1836.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Diaries.
- Children of Russell and Berthena Slayton
  The Children of Russell and Berthena Slayton series includes papers of Asa Walker Slayton, William Clark Slayton, and William's second wife, Julia A. Slayton. The Asa Walker Slayton papers document in part his service with the 25th Michigan Infantry during the Civil War. The William Clark Slayton papers are noteworthy for his diaries, 1857-1897, describing his life and activities as a Grattan Township, Kent County farmer. The diaries of Julia A. Slayton describe daily household activities, 1881 and 1883.
  - Asa Walker Slayton (b. 1830)
    - Papers,1849-1879, 39 folders (Box 1)
      (include letter, May 27, 1865 from Augustus W. Slayton about genealogy and his Civil War service with the 18th Michigan Infantry; and letters, March 28 and April 26, 1865, of Chester M. Slayton, corporal in Co. B, 25th Michigan Infantry during the Civil War containing comments to his brother Asa describing the final days of the war in North Carolina and the assassination of Abraham Lincoln)
    - Papers 1880-June 1893, 30 folders (Box 2)
    - Papers July 1893-January 1899, 20 folders (Box 3)
    - Papers February 1899-1907, 16 folders (Box 4)
    - Civil War miscellanea
      - Civil War Journal 1862-1864 (Box 4)
        (clippings of articles from Grand Rapids Weekly Eagle)
      - Pension claim papers (Box 4)
      - Orders, enlistment papers, applications for leave, etc. (Box 4)
        (include Orlando M. Poe letter, June 9, 1863)
      - Orders, reports on stolen supplies (Box 4)
      - Supply reports, etc. (Box 4)
    - Teachers contracts (Box 4)
    - Teaching certificates (Box 4)
  - William Clark Slayton (b. 1823)
    - Diaries, 1857-1879, 20 volumes (in 2 expandable folders) (Box 4)
    - Diaries, 1880-1897, 17 volumes (in 2 expandable folders) (Box 5)
  - Julia A. Slayton (second wife of William C. Slayton)
    - Diaries, 1881, 1883 (Box 5)
- Children of William C. and Sarah M. Slayton
  The Children of William C. and Sarah M. Slayton series includes papers of William Iambert Slayton, George A. Slayton, and George's wife, Sarah Abby Dunn Slayton. The William I. Slayton subseries includes his 1862 diary from his service as a soldier in Co. B, 25th Michigan Infantry during the Civil War. The George A. Slayton papers, ca. 1860-1927, concern his career as a teacher at Hillsdale College. The correspondence of George's wife, Sarah Abby Dunn Slayton also concerns Hillsdale College.
  - William Iambert Slayton (1844-1863)
    - Diary, January-July 1863 (Box 5)
      (also letter, 1863, from James Sage describing Slayton's death)
  - George A. Slayton
    - Autobiography 1927 (Box 5)
    - Diary 1888 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence 1898-1915, 17 folders (Box 5)
    - Correspondence 1916-1933, 31 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence 1934-1939, 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Letter to his mother 1860-1880 (Box 7)
    - GAR papers (Box 7)
    - Baptist Convention papers (Box 7)
  - Sarah Abby Dunn Slayton (wife of George A. Slayton)
    - Correspondence 1863-1908, 35 folders (Box 7)
    - Correspondence 1909-June 1918, 26 folders (Box 8)
    - Correspondence July 1918-1926, 15 folders (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 3 folders (Box 9)
- Children of George A. and Sarah Abby Dunn Slayton
  The Children of George and Sarah Slayton series consists of correspondence and other papers of Helen E. Slayton concerning Hillsdale College and the Hillsdale Baptist Convention; diaries, 1899-1918, of Helen's sister Sarah Augusta Slayton concerning Hillsdale College and her teaching activities. Other family members represented include Cyrena Slayton, Helen Dunn Gates, and Amelia Mead.
  - Helen E. Slayton
    - Correspondence 1900-1945, 22 folders (Box 9)
    - Correspondence 1946-1954, 7 folders (Box 10)
    - Hillsdale Baptist Convention
      - Correspondence 1928-1930 (Box 10)
      - Correspondence 1931 (Box 10)
      - Papers, 14 folders (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 3 folders (Box 10)
      (include Star Guild miscellanea)
    - Notebook re history of campus church at Hillsdale College 1855-1955, circa 1955 (Box 10)
  - Sarah Augusta Slayton (b. 1886)
    - Diaries 1899-1918, 9 volumes (in 1 expandable folder) (Box 10)
    - Letters of recommendation (Box 10)
  - Cyrena Slayton
    - Papers 1890-1920 (Box 10)
  - Helen Dunn Gates
    - Papers 1900-1919, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Amelia Mead
    - Papers 1913-1919 (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous
  The Miscellaneous series include papers relating to Hillsdale College alumni, greeting cards and programs, photographs, and later family material.
  - Commencement programs, greeting cards, etc. of Augusta and Helen Slayton, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Elon Reynolds / Abby Slayton papers 1905, 1907, 1920, 10 folders (Box 11)
    (locating names and addresses of Hillsdale College alumni)
  - Clinton Slayton collection of Slayton family materials (Box 11)
  - Photographs (Box 11)